THAO NGUYEN

W https://thaotn.me

E thao_nguyen@alumni.brown.edu

P 650,417,1018

Visual and digital product designer with experience in brand identity, illustration, graphic design, creative coding, and interactive prototyping.

Quick learner who loves impactful, empathetic user-facing work and is interested in social good and helping underserved communities.

EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE · NYC

Designer | Jan 2019 - Present

Owns complete internal brand system, including logo, visual system, assets, and animations.

Leads design workshops and sprints of 8-10 people.

Manages full UX research and design for a product, including analytics, user interviews, validation testing, prototyping, and development.

TIME INC · NYC

Web Designer/Developer | Aug 2017 - Jan 2019

Designed for InStyle, People, EW, and Essence, such as Fall TV Calendar and Essence Fest 2018 website.

SQUARE INC · SF

UX Engineer | Dec 2016 - June 2017

Managed full UX research and design for an internal product dealing with complex financial data, including iteration, testing, prototyping, and development.

EDUCATION

BROWN UNIVERSITY · PROVIDENCE, RI

BS Applied Math | Sept 2012 - May 2016

Computer Science, Web Applications, UI/UX, Software Engineering, Psychology, HCI

SCHOOL OF VISUAL ARTS · NYC

Continuing Education

Designing Brand Identity, Illustration, Graphic Design, UX Design, Typography, Form & Color

COMMUNITY OUTREACH

LGBT ASYLUM PROJECT · SF

Visual Designer | Feb 2021 - June 2021

Designed 2021 annual report, containing infographics, illustration spreads, and also refined the organization's visual system and guidelines..

SYLVIA RIVERA LAW PROJECT · NYC

UX Designer | Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

Designed workflow for incarcerated LGBTQ immigrants to receive legal help or contact legal assistance.

DSA · NYC

Lead UX Designer | Jan 2019 - Present

Designed marketing website, news site, and monthly event calendar to help activists organize.

SKILLS

Adobe CS (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects) Sketch, Figma, InVision, and other design/prototyping tools React Native, Typescript, HTML5/CSS3, Java, Python